# LINA LEKOVA

Software Engineer | Full-stack web developer

linkedin.com/in/lekova

github.com/lekova

twitter.com/linalekova

http://linalekova.com

lina.lekova@gmail.com

(781) 609-8789

I am self-motivated full stack web developer with background in software development as well as marketing and advertising. I am excited about learning new technologies and expanding my skill set. I love working in a team where I can be creative and exercise my expertise

# **SKILLS**

- **Object Oriented Programming**
- **Database Architecture**
- **Test-Driven Development**
- **AngularJS**
- Java
- **AJAX**
- **Ruby on Rails jQuery**
- **JavaScript**
- **Handlebars**
- Node.js
- HTML5
- **Express.js**
- CSS3
- mySQL
- **Bootstrap**
- **TSQL**
- Illustrator
- **PostgreSQL**
- Photoshop
- **MongoDB**
- **InDesign**

# **EXPERIENCE**



### Web Development Immersive at General Assembly

June 2015 - Sept 2015 | Boston, US

My previous experience as a software engineer was with desktop and enterprise technologies. I was eager to supplement my professional experience with web technologies. Joining GA's WDI allowed me to get hands-on, full-time web development experience with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, AngularJS, Handlebars, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.



#### Software Developer at Nemetschek Bulgaria

June 2011 - Mar 2013 | Sofia, Bulgaria

As part of the international .NET development team, I worked on application used for **3D visualization** and data exchange of an architectural/contractual elements. I participated in requirement discussions, prototyping sessions and software architecture planning. I designed and developed algorythms and user interfaces using C# 3.5. The tools used in the development process included Visual Studio 2008, MS **SQL Server** and **Perforce**.



# Marketing And Advertising Manager at PROFILINK Ltd

Oct 2007 - Apr 2011 | Plovdiv, Bulgaria

As an advertising specialist in a larger scale production company, my responsibilities were limited only to assuring best **quality** of collateral and media presence. With time and hard work I grew into a department manager. I had to establish effective working relations with contractors and advertising agencies, plan and manage events, as well as develop the company's market presence. The part I loved the most was working in a team.



#### Prepress And Design Specialist at Impress Bulgaria

June 2006 - Aug 2007 | Plovdiv, Bulgaria

My main responsibility in a small print company was to prepare advertising materials for the printing machines. Those varied from business cards, full-sized product catalogs, to product packaging and corporate vehicle branding. I used Adobe InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Acrobat, Corel **Draw and company-specific software** to keep track of work orders. I worked with clients on a daily basis to meet their visual design expectations and help them achieve their goals.

# EDUCATION



MS in Software Technologies

2006 - 2008 | Plovdiv, Bulgaria



**BS** in **Computer Science** 

2002 - 2006 | Plovdiv, Bulgaria